Henrik Wilhelmsen

SUMMARY

Henrik is a technical animator and game developer with over 6 years of experience working with animation in games.

As a technical animator on several projects at Ubisoft Stockholm, he has worked with animation tooling and pipeline development, prototyping and building tools with Python and PySide, as well as integrating and documenting existing tools and systems.

Additionally, he has experience with rigging and implementation of characters and animation, with both internal game-engines and with Unreal engine.

As narrative animator on Rage 2 and other titles, he gained experience working with in-game cinematics, narrative animation and dialogue systems.

Henrik also has a lot of experience working with motion capture, from getting into the suit himself with Xsens, planning and directing multi-actor shoots at both internal and external studios, assembly and re-targeting, animation cleanup, all the way to final implementation in-engine.

EXPERIENCE

Noid - Technical Animator

SEPTEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

Ubisoft Stockholm - Technical Animator

SEPTEMBER 2021 - September 2023

Ubisoft Stockholm - Animator

JANUARY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Avalanche Studios, Stockholm – Experienced Animator

APRIL 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

Avalanche Studios, Stockholm — Junior Animator

APRIL 2017 - APRIL 2018

EDUCATION

INN University, Hamar Norway — Bachelor's degree, Animation

AUGUST 2012 - JUNE 2015

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

iAnimate - Games Workshop 1
JANUARY 2016 - MARCH 2016

iAnimate – Games Workshop 2

APRIL 2016 - JUNE 2016

Udemy - Git and Github Bootcamp

JUNE 2022

Certificate url and id: ude.my/UC-6902d63b-bae4-4cce-ac43-6baf2dcdf0b2

Udemy - C++ Fundamentals

MAY 2023

Certificate url and id: ude.my/UC-5632fce2-0d41-4f35-a9df-94b6ac6014ba

SOFTWARE AND TECHNOLOGIES

Expert in

- Autodesk Maya
- Autodesk Motionbuilder

Comfortable with

- Python
- PySide/PyQt
- USD
- Git and Gitlab CI/CD
- Linux and WSL
- Unreal Engine
- Nvidia Omniverse

Learning

- C++
- Blender